Tyler Roberts

(262) 388-4050 | tjroberts314@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyleroberts | http://tyler.engineering

Summary

Enthusiastic computer engineer with 5+ years experience in software development and design. Most recently I've had the opportunity to work at a few startups which has allowed me to take on many responsibilities and force me out of my comfort zone. This has provided me with the opportunity to work on various code bases, across several teams, supporting numerous technologies.

Computer Skills - Python, Golang, Java, Javascript, C/C++, Git workflow, Linux, Cloud Services.

Experience

Amazon.com, Inc., Seattle, WA

Dec. 2019 - Present

Software Development Engineer, Alexa Personality

- Work on the Experiment and Design Tools teams, responsible for creating and running experiments for Alexa, and designing internal software for Alexa's content creators.
- Responsible for setting up the A/B testing, configuring, and driving of the "Now Listening" experiment for Alexa. Alexa had a new song she's lisenting to every day. Customer engagement increased at least 5% across all launched locales.
- Built core functionality in both the frontend and backend for an internal tool used to create and search for questions that Alexa can answer. Created backend APIs linked to the frontend, as well as their end-to-end tests.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS stack, Kotlin, Java, Javascript, React Framework, Git.

Cockroach Labs, New York, NY

May 2019 - Sep. 2019

Software Engineer, Bulk I/O

- Cockroach Labs is responsible for CockroachDB, the cloud-native, distributed SQL database.
- Work on the Bulk I/O team, which is responsible for bulk operations in the database, including backup and restore, and schema changes in the database.
- Fixed issue where the dump operation would include interleaved table statements inside of create table statements, causing dependency issues upon a restore.
- Designed features for the backup & restore process to include additional metadata about the cluster. Required a redesign of how the process worked, and reduced manual steps by the user.
- Tools & Technologies: Golang, SQL, Git/Github, Goland.

Dataminr, New York, NY

September 2018 - February 2019

Software Engineer, Content Search

- Work on developing the tools used to search and filter through the massive Twitter pipeline and other media sources.
- JVM code base comprised of Scala and Java. Applications ran on AWS, and much of the day to day work involved use with the AWS tech stack. Kinesis was used for processing the large data sources, where S3 was used to store the raw data.
- Migrated Pastebin data source from Kinesis to Kafka. Involved dependencies between several teams, and required collaboration amongst them.
- Tools & Technologies: Scala 2.11, Java 8, Maven, Docker, AWS, Google Guice, Git/Gitlab, IntelliJ, MacOS.

IBM Corporation, Yorktown Heights, NY

July 2017 - August 2018

Software Developer, Watson Health Cloud

- Developed Python application on another team that moved their locally stored data and user accounts to Bluemix, IBM's cloud platform as a service.
- Designed and engineered a web application from the ground up using HTML, CSS, Angular, and Bootstrap. Responsible for the front-end, including page navigation using an MVC design pattern.
- Tools & Technologies: Python (2.7), Docker, HTML, Angular, Javascript, Linux, PyCharm, MacOS.

UW-Madison Plasma Physics Dept., Madison, WI

Jan. 2016 - May 2017

Scientific Programmer

Intel Corporation, Hillsboro, OR

May 2016 - Aug. 2016

Pre-Silicon Validation Engineering Intern

Education

B.S. Computer Engineering, Computer Science, & Mathematics with Physics Certificate (minor). University of Wisconsin - Madison, May 2017